<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dison&#39; Website on Dison Obudho</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dison&#39; Website on Dison Obudho</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FullStack Responsive Food Delivery mobile App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/pizzaperk-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/pizzaperk-app/</guid>
      <description>App Link in Google Drive: PizzaPerk App&#xA;PizzaPerk Food Delivery Mobile App&#xA;The PizzaPerk Food Delivery app is a comprehensive mobile application built with Expo, showcasing a variety of advanced features and technologies:&#xA;Key Features and Technologies: Expo Libraries:&#xA;Utilized the latest Expo libraries, including expo-router for efficient navigation. Integrated expo-modules-core for enhanced modularity and functionality. Cart Logic:&#xA;Implemented a dynamic cart system where the total adjusts effectively when items are added or removed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FullStack Responsive Food Delivery Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/pizzaperk-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/pizzaperk-site/</guid>
      <description>Site Url: PizzaPerk Site&#xA;Project Overview: PizzaPerk Food Delivery Site Project Name: PizzaPerk&#xA;Tech Stack:&#xA;Frontend: Next.js (using SSR, parallel routes, intercepted routes), Redux for state management, TypeScript for type safety and error-free code. Backend: Supabase for database management and backend services. Testing: end-to-end and component testing(cypress) unit testing(jest and react testing library) Features and Functionality 1. Server-Side Rendering (SSR) Objective: Improve SEO and provide a faster initial load. Implementation: Key pages, such as the homepage, menu, and order details, are rendered on the server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazing React 19 New Features !!!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/use_react_hook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/use_react_hook/</guid>
      <description>Example: Fetching Data with use To demonstrate the use hook, let&amp;rsquo;s create a simple example that fetches data from an API.&#xA;Create a data fetching function: 1 2 3 4 5 const fetchData = async () =&amp;gt; { const response = await fetch(&amp;#39;https://jsonplaceholder.typicode.com/posts&amp;#39;); const data = await response.json(); return data; }; Use the use hook in your component: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 import React, { use } from &amp;#39;react&amp;#39;; const DataFetchingComponent = () =&amp;gt; { const data = use(fetchData()); return ( &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Fetched Data&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; {data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near Earth Object Web Service (NEOWS) Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/example-team-no-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/example-team-no-github/</guid>
      <description>Project Description: Near Earth Object Web Service (NEOWS) Website&#xA;I developed a responsive web application for the Near Earth Object Web Service (NEOWS) using a robust stack of modern web technologies. The project involved the following key aspects:&#xA;Frontend Development:&#xA;React: Utilized React to build a dynamic and interactive user interface. TypeScript: Implemented TypeScript to enhance code quality and maintainability with strong typing and error checking. Chakra UI: Employed Chakra UI for a consistent and accessible design system, ensuring a polished and user-friendly experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontend Developer Assessment Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/first-blog/</guid>
      <description>There were a total of 5 questions involved in this react interview. The time limit for the interview was 8 hours. However, finishing all the questions was not mandatory. Near Earth Object Web Service(Neows) API was used to generate data for the UI.&#xA;The assesment was based on:&#xA;Appearance and UX of your web app Maintainability and Quality of your code General approach to solve problems Use of dependencies other than required ones Your own time management and prioritisation Required Dependencies were: ✔ node16+ ✔ npm8+ ✔ react (latest) ✔ typescript (latest) ✔ github ✔ axios and react-query ( https://react-query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Portfolio Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I created my portfolio website using Hugo and UIKit, it serves as an online resume containing all my work.&#xA;This has been created as a theme so that others can use and adapt it.&#xA;Sections Homepage The homepage provides the basic information about you, including links to social media, skills you have, things you&amp;rsquo;ve done and your education. This page makes good use of UIKit grid and cards for organising all the information and ensuring it is responsive to work on mobile devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FullStack Responsive Ecommerce Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/react/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/react/</guid>
      <description>Responsive Furniture Website Project Overview Developed a modern, responsive furniture website to showcase my proficiency in front-end design, CSS, animations, JavaScript, and React, with backend integration using Django Rest Framework. This project highlights my ability to create aesthetically pleasing, user-friendly interfaces and implement dynamic functionalities for an enhanced user experience.&#xA;Key Features Responsive Design: Utilized advanced CSS techniques, including Flexbox and Grid, to ensure the site is fully responsive and looks great on all devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FullStack Responsive Food Delivery Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/food/</guid>
      <description>Project Title: Responsive Food Delivery Web Application&#xA;Description: Developed a responsive web application for a food delivery service, demonstrating expertise in front-end and back-end development. This project showcases my ability to design and implement a modern, user-friendly interface with seamless functionality.&#xA;Key Features:&#xA;User Interface Design: Created an intuitive and visually appealing design using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, ensuring a cohesive and engaging user experience. Responsive Design: Implemented responsive design principles using CSS and media queries to ensure the application is accessible and functional across various devices, including desktops, tablets, and smartphones.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FullStack Responsive Gym Website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/gym/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/gym/</guid>
      <description>Gym Fitness Website Project Project Overview: I developed a comprehensive and responsive Gym Fitness website to showcase my expertise in modern web development technologies. This project highlights my skills in front-end design, CSS, animations, JavaScript, React, and my familiarity with Django Rest for backend integration.&#xA;Key Features:&#xA;Responsive Design: Implemented a fully responsive layout to ensure optimal viewing across a wide range of devices, from mobile phones to large desktop screens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React and Nodejs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/realestate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/realestate/</guid>
      <description>React Public Site Link: Real Estate Website&#xA;Responsive Portfolio Website Project Title: Responsive Design with CSS, Nodejs and Figma&#xA;Introduction: I developed a responsive Real Estate website to demonstrate my skills in CSS, Node.js, and web design. The site serves as a personal portfolio to showcase my work, skills, and experience as a web developer.&#xA;Technologies Used:&#xA;Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript Backend: Node.js, Express.js Design Tools: Figma, Adobe Photoshop Features:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Nextjs 14 App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/example-team-no-github-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/example-team-no-github-copy/</guid>
      <description>E-Commerce Platform with Server-Side Rendering&#xA;Developed a sophisticated e-commerce website leveraging Next.js for server-side rendering (SSR) to ensure optimal performance and SEO. Utilized TypeScript for type safety, enhancing code reliability and maintainability. Integrated Prisma for efficient data management and querying with a NoSQL database, enabling scalable and flexible data handling.&#xA;Key Features:&#xA;Server-Side Rendering (SSR): Implemented with Next.js to enhance page load times and improve SEO by pre-rendering pages on the server.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
